I'm off! I'm off!
Mokku, be careful out there.
I know!
He's really changed. He's become so dependable.
Let's see... no, no.
The folks in this village don't eat anything decent.
Honestly... do they really want us to starve to death? Good grief... Huh?
How mysterious...
The scent of meat!
You bastard!
Trying to hog it all to yourself, you damn jerk!
I wonder why.
Oh, give me a break. Huh?
Here comes Mokku.
Where do you think he's heading?
Well, well, well, where are you off to, little Mokku?
Oh, Kenken. I'm going to town for Grandpa to order some new woodcarving tools.
To town, huh? I wonder why...
Maybe we should tag along with you?
It's all right. I can go by myself. See you later!
Hmph, he's gotten awfully cocky lately.
Town, huh? Haven't been there in a while.
You thieving cat!
I-I'm a weasel! I wonder why.
This place is amazing. There's so much stuff here.
No, no. Don't get distracted. Straight to the tool shop.
Let's see, where's the tool shop...
Watch out! Get out of the way!
Clack-clack, that's so cool.
But pushing me aside and not even apologizing...
All right!
Hey, you!
What?
Where is First Street?
How should I know? I always ride in a carriage.
Hey, that was dangerous! I almost got hit by a bus!
That's because you were daydreaming, country bumpkin.
What's a country bumpkin?
It means an idiot.
What did you say?
Chikaro?
Let's go!
Who on earth was that guy?
First Street isn't that way!
You're supposed to go straight to the tool shop!
That's why I'm looking for the way!
And I'm telling you that's the wrong way!
I can go this way too!
Mokku, the city is full of strange folks. You'll never get anywhere if you let them bother you!
Come on, hurry up and finish your errand!
I know that. But he is going somewhere. I'll keep an eye on him for a bit.
Don't worry, it's going to be okay.
Mokku! You can't do that!
Oh, he's eating it. He looks just like a human.
Madame, please have a seat.
Chikaro is as cute as ever.
He's quite a handful with his mischief.
Chikaro, go play in the garden for a bit.
Yes.
Hey, you!
Hey there, country bumpkin. Still lost?
I followed you here. You're not human, are you?
I am a chimpanzee, an ape far superior to humans!
Are apes really superior to humans?
Apes were born into this world long before humans ever were!
But humans can make all kinds of things and seem to do anything.
Humans just multiply like rats and do everything through sheer numbers.
We ape kind prefer living peacefully in Mother Nature. Who are you, anyway?
You're made of wood, huh?
Yeah. Just a wooden puppet. Though I want to become a human.
Why would a puppet want to become a human?
Huh? Do you have any idea how much puppets get made fun of?
Hmm, I-I see. If you became a real human—no, something even greater than human, everyone would be amazed.
Forget being more than human, just being human is enough! You know so much, so please, teach me about humans.
I really don't like dealing with troublesome things.
Hey wait!
There's no greater teacher than you! Please!
Take me as your apprentice...
I'm pretty strict. Are you sure about this?
I'm so glad I came to town!
Thief!
You idiot! Run, quick!
Right away, Brother!
Wait!
Brother!
Hanamuro, stop!
That's enough!
I'm sorry, they got away.
Who are you?
I'm Mokku. Starting today, I'm Mr. Chikaro's apprentice.
Chikaro's apprentice?
Yes.
Well, how interesting. All right. If you're Chikaro's apprentice, you're more than welcome. Come on inside.
Thank you very much.
(Children screaming)
What on earth are you doing? This is how you play the piano.
(Music)
Such wonderful music.
This is the power of amateur music!
This is the primal cry. The rhythm of our monkey clan.
Stop it!
Stop that! Such vulgar music!
You've been a bad boy lately, haven't you?
Isn't it because you took this strange puppet as an apprentice?
Making me out to be the bad guy... Acting so refined when you don't know anything... Seriously! We were just having fun!
*Sigh*... I am sorry... You get carried away way too easily. You'll never rule the world like that.
Go cool your head!
Yes, sir.
What does "catching lightning" mean?
And what good does cooling my head do?
Oh, you guys!
Hey, Hanaguro, Mokku's got some real skill, doesn't he?
Sure does. Managed to slip right into a huge mansion.
And when you think about it, that's thanks to us. Right, Mokku? You get that, don't you?
Heh-heh-heh, 'cause we pulled off that theft back then, you get to live such a nice life.
What did you guys come to town for?
There are lots of humans in town. Lots of humans means lots of food.
Heh-heh-heh, wonder why.
Then why don't you go look for food in town?
This is someone else's place.
But isn't this your home, too?
I'm just an apprentice, so... Take that!
Yah!
You'd better cool off!
I did cool off, but they're crazy about that monkey on the train!
Monkeys are totally outdated!
Outdated? That's not true!
That's right! You'll see!
They can't run as fast as us, their senses aren't sharp, and they don't even blow foul air!
Besides, when we die, we leave our hides behind. What the hell do they do?
So that makes you guys better?
Naturally. How about you bring us something to eat?
No way!
Hey, Boss, should we use our usual trick?
Huh?!
(Laughs)
B-B...
Hey, I hear Mokku is weak against fire!
If you don't bring us food, this house might just burn down while you and Sara are asleep!
Boo-hoo!
(Laughs)
Getting three meals a day for us should be easy enough, right, little Mokku?
A-All right. I'll bring it.
Our hideout is behind the flowerbed. We'll be waiting, Mokku.
Where could Mokku have gone?
Did he get lost, or did someone take him away?
It was too much for him to go alone... Yes, I'll go to town, too.
We're going to Mrs. Shiraishi's party today, so let's get all dressed up.
Mokku, get the bath ready for Caro.
I heard foxes and weasels run faster than you.
So what? Lower animals are the ones that have to run and jump around.
They prey on anything weaker than them, and have to run for their lives the moment they see something stronger.
So that's why they're always running away in such a hurry.
They?
Yeah, some old acquaintances of mine.
I see.
Don't waste your time on worthless fools. We're going to become a species more advanced than humans.
I just want to be human.
Aim higher.
I don't care about aiming high, I just want to quit doing this.
You've gotten quite rebellious lately.
It's not that, but are monkeys really better than humans?
Are you mocking me?
No, no, of course not...
Something's off with that Mokku.
Cake! Cake! Cake!
Let's go. Mokku, not bad, huh?
Boss, Mokku brought it.
Oh, Mokku, good job, good job.
Here, it's cake.
Boss, what about drinks?
Oh, right. Hey, there's wine, isn't there? Go on.
It should be in the cellar. You know what'll happen if you don't bring it.
All right.
Here you go.
(Shielding from the sun)
(Sinister male voice)
Thank you. (Sinister male voice)
Ah, so that's what you're doing. No good. (Sinister male voice)
Karon! Help!
Karon! Karon! Karon!
Help me! Come on, listen to me!
You really tricked your way into this house, didn't you!
Just wait, I'll toss you into the fireplace along with the junk! Prepare yourself!
That's the thing! They said they'd burn the whole house down, so I gave them food... As if I'd fall for such a cheap act!
I'd rather throw it away than feed petty thieves like them!
Damn it...
Mokku, how are your accommodations?
Hikaron! Let me out, hurry!
Ending up as firewood is your destiny. Just give up.
Won't you even try to save your apprentice?
I was a fool to trust a wooden puppet.
Now then, I'll head to the party and tease those noble ladies.
Caro! Help me!
Caro! Caro!
Solly!
Don't cry, little lady. I'll scold him soundly later. Shall we dance?
Still alive and kicking.
No, no, wake up.
Who gave you permission to come here...?
Filthy bastard! I won't even speak to him! You talk to him!
Right! Mother got in the way!
If I'm not here, Mother will starve! Just get out!
Idiot! What are you talking about?!
Next time, you bring the food!
Like hell I'd do that for you!
Don't act so high and mighty, you monkey bastard!
Shall we get him?
Get him!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
Stop that at once!
Shut up!
This is terrible!
They've come for revenge!
(monkey screeches)
Damn it...
What is it?
Boss!
Goodbye!
How dare you humiliate me at the party! In the end, you're nothing but a savage monkey. You're better suited as a circus clown.
Damn it, let me out of the shed! What's your problem? This is awful!
I don't want this! I don't want to be sold to the circus! Stop it!
Am I going to be burned?
Mokku! By apprenticing to a monkey...
...did you become a bit more like one? / No! I'm going to become human! Hurry and take off these chains!
Just mimicking the look and shape of a human is not enough.
Strength is a good example. Do you understand?
Then what am I supposed to do?
You must not rush. You need to build yourself up step by step.
What do you mean, step by step?
You must experience many things and learn about the world.
And once you learn to tell right from wrong, you will be able to become human.
It will be hard. But you must never give up, Mokku.
[[NO AUDIO]]
I don't want to be in the circus.
You're good at the piano and acrobatics, the circus audience will love you. No, no way!
I'll be burned to ashes before I ever find a human heart.
Yeah.
Aaaargh! Huh?!
Ha ha ha! This is a fine monkey! Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Well then, ma'am, I'll be taking the monkey.
Take him away already. Looking at such a filthy monkey will upset my sweet little Marianne. Won't it, dear?
I don't want to be a circus freak! Mokku, do something!
Geez...
No, no! Save me, Mokku!
Mokku! Mokku!
Hikaron, you're full of energy.
Ma'am!
Don't treat animals like toys. Please truly care for them.
Mokku, is that you, Mokku?
Grandpa.
Mokku.
It's all right now. I don't like seeing that sad face.
Cheer up, Mokku.
Grandpa!
I'm sorry. I'm so useless.
Grandpa made it back, so there's no need to worry.
Grandpa!
Mokku makes friends with an orphaned chick.
To Mokku, this lonely baby stork feels just like a little brother.
One day, the chick is shot and wounded, but survives thanks to the tender care of Mokku and his friends.
Yet as the chick grows day by day, it is destined to grow up and journey to its distant homeland.
Look forward to next week's Kashi no Ki Mokku!